Guide to the Brooklyn letterhead collection BCMS.0008
Brooklyn Collection
- Mayflower Plumbing and Heating, 1936
  Plumbing and heating. 1803 Stillwell Avenue
- McAuley, J.H., 1869
  Heaters and stoves dealer. 300 Fulton Street, opp. Johnson
- McBeath, William Jr., 1896
  Stationer and printer. 62nd Street, near 14th Avenue
- McBride, B., 1884
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 101, 134 York Street
- McBride, B., 1889
- McCaldin Brothers, 1879
  Coal and wood dealer. 21 S. William Street
- McCann, Bernard & Co., 1860, 1880, 1883, 1887, 1888
  Stoves, ranges and heaters. 273 Fulton Avenue., cor. St. Felix Street; 739 Fulton Street; 61 Lafayette Ave., junction Fulton Ave.
- McCarthy, D., 1881
  Shipwright and caulker. Elizabeth Street, near Richard
- McCarty, Ormonde, 1936-1938
  Plumbing and heating contractor. 4515 Avenue N
- McCarty, Thomas B., 1896
  Painter and paper hanging. 276 Smith St. & 220 Wyckoff St.
- McClellan, C.R., M.D., 1867
  Doctor. 107 Pacific St.
- McCloskey, George M., 1881, 1883
  Plumbing, gas and steam fitting. 191-1/2 Atlantic Avenue
- McCloskey, John / McCloskey & Gorman, 1866, 1867, 1869
  Painters, glaziers and paper hangers. 2 Henry Street, cor. of Fulton
- John McComb, 1891
  Painter. 85 Orange Street
- McCormack, Francis X., 1947
  Lawyer. 1491 Flatbush Avenue
- McCormick, J. & Co., 1884, 1893
  Shoe store. 282, 485 Fulton Street
- McCormick, John, 1895, 1897
  Dry goods. Ninth Street, corner Fifth Avenue
- McCormick & Knox, 1892, 1896
  Plumbing and gas fitter. 105 Broadway & 100 South 6th Street
- McCrodden, Elmer A., 1937
  Plumber. 91 Conklin Avenue
- McDicken, Alex, 1907
  Greengrocer. 142 West Avenue
- McDonald, Albert G., 1883
  Attorney. 16 Court Street
- McDonald, Alfred, 1877
  Painter and decorator. 43-1/2 Ormond Place
- McDonald, Archibald, 1889
  Plumber and gas fitter. 696 Myrtle Ave., near Bedford Ave.
- M'Donald, John, 1870, 1872
  Plumber and gas fitter. 85, 97 Cranberry Street, near Fulton
- McDonald, William, 1884
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 83 Cranberry Street, near Fulton
- McElhinney & Stewart, 1863
  Dry goods. 192 Fulton Street
- McGann, Raymond F., 1938
  Real estate. 2935 Avenue R
- McGarvey, Alexander, 1872, 1874
  Plumber. 372 Myrtle Avenue
- McGee & Treacy, 1880
  Musical instrument dealer. 77 Court Street, cor. Livingston
- McGinness, Chas. J., 1882
  Horseshoer. 220 Broadway
- McGovern, Charles H., 1883
  Stables. 46 to 50 Love Lane
- McGovern, Thomas, 1894
  Undertakers' supplies. 39 South 8th Street
- McGrath, Peter, 1898
  Horseshoer. 43 Henry Street, bet. Cranberry & Middagh
- M'Gratty, P.H., 1876
  Marble dealer. 276 East Baltic Street, cor. Court
- McHugh, P., 1903
  Plasterer and mason. 131 Greenpoint Avenue
- McKeefrey, John, 1889
  Mason and builder. 68 North Portland Ave.
- McKeever, S.W., 1880, 1888
  Plumber and steam fitter. 95 Washington Street, near York
- McKenna, James, 1886
  Saddle maker. 215-1/2 Park Ave., near Vanderbilt
- McKeon, John, 1889
  Iron works. 220 Skillman St.
- McKeon & Todd, 1879, 1887
  Tailors. Southwest corner Broadway and Fourth Street
- McKnight, Alexander, 1884, 1888, 1889, 1893
  Carpenter and builder. 370, 864 Bedford Ave., north of Myrtle; 158 Walworth St., south of Myrtle
- McLaughlin, Charles A., 1888
  Insurance. Dime Bank Building, cor. Court & Remsen Sts.
- McLeay, Thos. W. / McLeay & Weller, 1866-1867
  Plumber and gas fitter. Old 294, new 878 Fulton Ave., bet. Oxford St. & Portland Ave.
- McMahon, George, 1874
  Coal and wood dealer. Corner of Richard St. and Hamilton Avenue
- McManus, Philip, 1906
  Coal, wood, and ice dealer. 246 Bond Street
- McMurdo, James, 1916
  Carpenter and builder. 1069 Fulton St.
- McNally, Owen, 1870
  Shoe maker. 915 Myrtle Avenue, bet. Bedford and Skillman
- M'Namara, Edward, 1867
  Plumber and gas fitter. 76 South Seventh Street, cor. Third
- M'Namara, H., 1868, 1871
  Plumber and gas fitter. 92, 98 Myrtle Ave.
- McNaughton, M., 1870
  Carpenter and builder. 201 Fort Greene Pl., near Atlantic Ave.
- McNeill Real Estate, 1939
  Real estate. 1623 Kings Highway
- McQuade, John & Co., 1906
  Paint manufacturer. 416-418 Marcy Avenue
- McQuaid, John, 1883
  Mason and builder. 257 Humboldt St., or 80 Bushwick Ave. cor. of Devoe St.
- McShane, Henry & Co. / Henry McShane Mfg. Co., 1888, 1898
  Plumbing materials maker. 17 to 27 So. Third Street, cor. 1st; 50 and 52 Myrtle Ave and 359 Pearl Street
- McVee & Bourke, 1867
  Wheelwrights and blacksmiths. 75 Congress St., bet. Hicks & Columbia
- Mead, Henry C., 1876
  Sash and blind maker. Union Avenue, bet. North Second & Devoe Sts.
- Mead & Randolph, 1868
  Merchant tailors. 312 & 314 Fulton Street
- Mead, S.H., 1867
  Clothing store. 314 Fulton Street
- Meade, James M., 1888
  Shoe store. 139 Myrtle Avenue
- Meade, P.'s Son, 1900
  Horseshoer. 608 Humboldt Street
- Meadon, T.J., 1873, 1888
  Sheet iron worker. 51 Greenpoint Avenue
- Meadowbrook Park Civic Association
  Valentine Road, Westbury
- Mechanics Bank, 1929
  356-358 Fulton Street
- Mechanics Fire Insurance Company, 1863
  1 Montague Street
- Mechanics and Traders Bank of Brooklyn, 1899
- Mechanics and Traders Exchange, 1870, 1901
  359 Fulton Street
- Medical Society of the County of Kings, 1924
  1313 Bedford Avenue
- Medical Society of the County of Kings, Directory for Nurses, 1893
  356 Bridge Street
- Medicus, C.M., 1883
  Furniture maker. 45, 47 & 49 Dekalb Avenue
- Meehan, James F., 1909
  Ice dealer. 5011 Sixth Avenue
- Meehan, James J., 1884, 1887
  Plumber and gas fitter. 494 Myrtle Ave., near Ryerson St.
- Meeks Bros., 1925
  Plumbing and heating. 473 52nd Street
- Meeks & Inch, 1878
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 774 Gates Avenue
- Meighan, Thomas C., 1868
  Plumber. 194 Court Street, bet. Harrison and Degraw
- Melnick, J.A. Company, 1938
  Millwork distributors. 51st Street, First to Second Ave.
- Melville, Andrew, 1865, 1870, 1871
  Plumber and gas fitter. 340 Atlantic St., near Hoyt St.
- Mendalis, Samuel, 1932
  Insurance broker. 245 Troy Avenue
- Mentzinger, C.F. & T.D., 1878, 1883
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 192 Broadway, & 191 South 8th St., bet. 5th & 6th
- Mercantile Library, Trustees of the, 1865-1866
- Merlin, Robt., 1893
  Carpenter and builder. 166 South Portland Avenue
- Mermaid Avenue Hand Laundry
  Laundry. 2017 Mermaid Avenue
- Mermelstein, Benny, 1944-1945
  Roofer. 2017 Surf Avenue
- Merrill & Son, T.C., 1877
  Coal and wood dealer. 9 Bond Street, near Fulton Street
- Mersereau Manufacturing Co., The, 1894
  Makers of metal objects. 124-130 Pearl St.
- Meruk & May, 1914
- Meseritz, L., 1920
  Men's haberdasher. 857 Flatbush Ave., near Martense Street
- Meserole, Walter M., C.E., 1895
  Civil engineer and surveyor. cor. Atlantic and Van Siclen Aves.
- Metcalfe, J.C., 1880
  Decorator. 1250 Fulton Street and 472 Myrtle Avenue
- Metropolitan Civic Association, 1928
  Spiegel's Hall, 1455 Metropolitan Ave., cor. Emma St.
- Metropolitan Coal Yard, 1890
  Coal dealer. Metropolitan Ave., Newtown Creek
- Metropolitan Gas Light Co. Brooklyn, 1890, 1894, 1895
  Gas company. 563 Atlantic Avenue, near Flatbush Avenue
- Metropolitan Hobby Sales, 1940
  Wholesale hobby kits. 746A Utica Ave.
- Metropolitan Iron Foundry, 1890
  Iron foundry. 54 and 56 Metropolitan Avenue
- Metropolitan Plate Glass Insurance Co., of N.Y., 1887
  John E. Seward, Manager. 74 Broadway
- Metropolitan Rod & Gun Club, 1934
  Sports Club. 230 Flatbush Avenue
- Metz, William, 1867
  Newspaper distributor. 121 Court Street
- Meurer Bros. Co., 1897, 1909
  Sheet metal makers. 567-577 Flushing Ave. & 266 & 268 Wallabout St.
- Meyer, Frank C. Co. Inc., 1927
  Shoebox maker. 259 Lexington Avenue
- Meyer, I.R., 1928
  Real estate. 242 Sumner Avenue
- Meyer, Louis Co., Inc., 1929
  Meat products. Wyckoff and Cooper Avenues
- Meyer, William, 1906
  Painter and decorator. Formerly Theo Meyer. 1079 Myrtle Avenue, near Lewis Ave.
- Meyerrose, Richard & Co., 1883
  Feed and fertilizer dealers. 1577, 1579 and 1581 Myrtle Avenue
- Meyer's, 1944
  Glass dealer. 2323 Surf Avenue
- Meyers, E.H., 1914
  Coal dealer. 211-219 Kent Ave., near Metropolitan Ave.
- Middendorf, Wm. H., 1879
  Grocer. 427 Court St., cor. 3rd Place
- Mienhardt, J.F., circa late 1800s
  Hardware dealer. 402 Grand Street
- Milham, O.H.A., 1899, 1904
  Furnace maker and roofer. 61 Lafayette Ave., junction Fulton St.
- Milkman's Millinery House
  Hat Shop. 442 & 444 Fulton Street, 995 Broadway, cor. Dittmar St.
- Miller, B. & Co., 1906
  Carpenters. 73 Bartlett Street
- Miller, C.J., 1901
  Painting and decorating. 205 & 207 State Street
- Miller, E., 1881, 1883
  Teacher
- Miller, Ellman Co.
  Carpet dealer. 391 Grand Street
- Miller, F., M.D., 1872
  Doctor
- Miller & Howe, 1887
  Carpenters and builders. 496 Clermont Ave.
- Miller & Van Winkle, 1894
  Steel wire and springs maker. 18-24 Bridge Street and 80-88 John St.
- Miller, Wm. P. Co., 1891
  Lubricant dealer. 100 Greenpoint Avenue
- Mills, A.F., 1868, 1873
  Plumber and gas fitter. 478, 483 Atlantic Street, bet. Nevins and Powers/3rd Ave.
- Mills Brothers, 1926
  Furniture dealers. 1720 Broadway
- Mills & Bush, 1881, 1883
  Carpenters and builders. 74 St. James Place
- Mills, William, 1889
  Painter and paper hanger. 183 Driggs Street
- Mills, William & Son, 1867
  Merchant tailors. 63 Fourth Street
- Milne & McMillan, 1893
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 325 Adams Street
- Milne, Peter & Son, 1863, 1865-1868
  Plumbers, gas and steam fitters. 133 (new 127) Fulton St., opposite Middagh; 13 High Street
- Miner, A.D., 1921
  Superintendent, Betholom Fields and Shearith Israel Cemeteries. Kills Path, Cyprus Hills
- Mitchell, Chauncy L., M.D., 1859
  Doctor.
- Mitchell, Thomas, 1898
  Watchman. c/o White Star Towing Co., Hunter's Point Bridge, Long Island City
- Modern Auto Top Co., The, 1916
  Auto top makers. 1226 Bedford Ave.
- Mohegan Tube Company, The, 1917, 1920
  Tube makers. Scott Avenue & Meserole Street
- Mold, A.L., 1868
  Bonnet maker. 186 Fulton Street
- Mollenhauer, Henry College of Music, 1889, 1890, 1891
  Music school. 73 Livingston Street
- Moller & Schumann, 1896
  Varnish maker. Cor. Marcy and Flushing Aves.
- Monahan, H.V., 1890
  Furniture and carpet dealer. 503-509 Fith Avenue, 12th & 13th Sts.
- Mone, Thomas E. Jr., 1928
  Real estate and insurance. 1000 Bedford Avenue
- Montauk Fire Insurance Company, The, 1863, 1865, 1877
  7, 22 Court Street
- Montauk Livery and Boarding Stable, 1894
  Stable. 251 & 253 St, Marks Avenue, near Vanderbilt
- Montauk Paint Manufacturing Co., 1911
  Paint makers. 170-172 Second Ave, cor. 13th St.
- Montignani, Stewart & Co., 1880
  Painters suppliers. 229 Bridge St., 390 Myrtle Ave., 201 Smith St.
- Moody, Leonard, 1898
  Real estate. 746 Washington Avenue, cor. Park Place
- Mooney, A.C., 1878
  Milliner. 411 Fulton St.
- Mooney, Hugh J., 1888, 1899
  Painter and paper hanger. 334 Smith Street; 68 Seventh Avenue
- Moore, Benjamin & Co., 1887, 1892, 1903
  Paint manufacturer. 244 to 262 Water St. cor. Adams
- Moore, Henry D., 1880
  Luggage maker. Cor. Fulton and Johnson Sts.
- Moore, James L., 1882
  Saddle maker. 21 Fulton St.
- Moore, M., 1895
  Stone dealer. Benson Ave. and West End R.R. [railroad]
- Moore, W.F. Jr., 1894
  Carriage rentals. 69 Pennsylvania Avenue
- Moorehead, Alexander, 1890
  House painter. Flatbush Avenue, opp. Reformed Dutch Church
- Mootry, Thomas H., 1890
  Mason and plasterer. 145 North Second Street
- Moquin & Offerman / Moquin-Offerman-Heissenbuttel Coal Co., 1888, 1898, 1899
  Coal dealer. On pier foot of Adams St.; 746 Washington Ave.; 20 Court St.; 309 Flatbush Ave.
- Moran, J.W. & H.C., 1875
  Stone dealer. Hamilton Avenue, cor. Hicks St.
- Moran, John, 1886, 1902
  Mason and plasterer, contractor. 1431 Fulton Street
- Moran, M., 1866-1868
  Metalware. 107 Atlantic Street
- Moran, Wm. J., 1896
  Mason and builder. 141 South 5th Street
- Morehouse, Wilmot Lincoln, 1898
- Morgan & Anderson, 1870
  Stone cutters. King, cor. of Ferris Street, Atlantic Dock
- Morgan, Benjamin, 1914
  Carpenter and builder. 443 Shepherd Avenue
- Morgan, Gene, 1888
  Furniture maker. 286 Grand Street
- Morgan, George, 1887
  Mason and builder. 453 Fifth Avenue
- Morgan, H.P. & Co., 1863, 1868
  Linens [?]. 245 Fulton Street
- Morgan, William, 1866, 1870
  Real estate. 50 South 7th Street, cor. First Street; 45 Broadway
- Morgenthaler, Jacob, 1889-1891
  Door and window maker. 278-284 Schermerhorn Street
- Morrell, J.R., 1889
  Painter. 343 Nostrand Avenue
- Morris, A., 1880
  Glass dealer. 157 Grand Street
- Morris, G., 1881-1882
  Glazier. 105 Court Street, bet. Schermerhorn and State
- Morris, L.S., 1883
  House painter. 426 Gates Avenue
- Morris & Selover, 1874
  Carpenters and builders. Corner DeKalb Ave. and Debevoise St.
- Morrissey, Richard, 1929
  Window shades maker. 504 Fifth Avenue
- Morsch, Charles Fr., 1889-1890
  Paint and wallpaper dealer, painters' supplies. 308 Ellery St., near Broadway
- Morse Dry Dock and Repair Co., 1907
  Engineers and boiler makers. Foot 55th to 57th Sts.
- Morse & Stern
  Printers. 35 Myrtle Avenue
- Morton, Andrew, 1896
  Corks maker. 643-647 Kent Ave.
- Morton, John & Son(s) / John Morton's Sons & Co., 1870, 1886, 1888, 1890, 1899
  Builders materials dealer. Carroll Street and Gowanus Canal
- Moseley, Chas. H. & Co., 1882
  Dental materials maker. 197 and 199 Grand Street
- Moser, Chas. H., 1910, 1914
  Mens and boys outfitter. 1311 Fulton Street
- Moser, J.J. & Co., 1880-1881
  Dry goods. 288 Court Street
- Moses, William, 1887
  281 St. James Place
- Mount Carmel Cemetery, 1926
  Fresh Pond Road and Cypress Avenue
- Mount Carmel Cemetery Association
  Box 93, Ridgewood P.O.
- Mount, John L. & Co., 1897
  Horse foot remedy maker. 273 Central Ave.
- Mount Lebanon Cemetery, 1946
  Myrtle Avenue and Forest Park
- Mowbray, Andrew, 1887
  Boarding stable. 233 Schermerhorn St., near Bond St.
- Muchmore, John, 1869
  Coal dealer [?]. Cor. Washington and Plymouth Sts.
- Mueller, B., 1899
  Horseshoer. 411 Flushing Avenue
- Mugford & William J. Callahan, 1879
  House painter. 331 Court Street
- Mulhallon, Wm. E., M.D., 1867
  Doctor. 3 Lafayette Avenue
- Mullen, Mrs. J., 1880
  Dry goods dealer. 83 York Street
- Mullen, Thos. H., 1900
  Undertaker and embalmer. 714 Union Street
- Mller, George P., 1884
  Cabinet maker. 22 Sumner Avenue
- Muller, J.H., 1887, 1889
  Grocer. 317 Broadway, cor. 10th Street / 359 Broadway, cor. Keap Street
- Muller, Jacob, 1887
  Saddle and harness maker. 830 Fulton St., near Vanderbilt Ave.
- Mullon, George W., 1875
  Agricultural implements maker. 89 North 2nd St. [formerly 257 First Street]
- Mullon, John, 1876
  Iron works. 40 Union Avenue
- Mullon, Wm., 1884
  Iron works. 313 to 317 South Third Street
- Mulqueen, John, 1876, 1887, 1896
  Carpeting and house goods. 67 Myrtle Avenue, cor. Jay Street
- Mumby, George W., 1865
  Flour and grain dealer. 59 Fulton Street
- Mumford, W. & H., 1863
  Feather beds and pillow dealer. 218 and 200 Fulton Street
- Mundell & Avila, 1865
  House and sign painters. 135 Fulton St.
- Mundell, David & Co., 1874
  Boot and shoe maker. 298 Fulton Street, near Pierrepont St.
- Mundell, John K., 1867
  Fish, oysters, clams, and lobsters dealer. 33 Myrtle Avenue
- Mundell, Roberts & Sons / J. Mundell & Son, 1881, 1885
  Shoe dealer. 298 Fulton Street, near Pierrepont; 303 Fulton St., near Johnson
- Municipal Court of the City of New York, 1931
  27 Snyder Avenue
- Municipal Court, City of New York, Borough of Brooklyn, 1942
  42nd St and 4th Avenue, New York NY
- Municipal Lodge B'nai B'rith, 1964-1965
  2686 Ocean Avenue; 25 Parade Place
- Murphy, M.T., 1860
  Merchant tailor. 71 Court Street, two doors from Atlantic
- Murphy & Becker, 1946
  Plumbing and heating. 2559-2561 Nostrand Ave.
- Murphy & Morris, 1881
  Painter and paper hanging. 426 Gates Avenue
- Murphy, P.W., 1898
  Fish monger. 140 Court Street
- Murphy, Thos. J., 1883
  Bill Poster
- Murray, A., 1885
  Granite and marble works. Near the entrance to Calvary Cemetery
- Murray, Garrett, 1885
  Bottle dealer. 62 Henry Street
- Murray, J.E. & Co., 1887, 1889
  Furniture dealer. 201 Grand Street
- Murray, Lindley Z.
  Furniture dealer. 59, 61, and 63 Myrtle Avenue
- Murray, Wm. F., 1887-1888
  Plumber and gas fitter. 436 Degraw Street, near Hoyt; removed to 318 Court Street; 334 Smith Street
- Musaus, John Sons, 1931
  Heating contractors. 5912 New Utrecht Avenue
- Mutell, W., 1874, 1876
  Plumber and gas fitter. 256, 262 Columbia Street, bet. President & Carroll
- Mutual Company, The, 1896
  Boat towing. 27 New York Produce Exchange
- My-T-Fine Corporation, 1930
  Baking supplies. 882 Third Avenue
- Myers, Jos. S., 1890
  Sign and banner painter. Geo. F. Zeiler, successor. 335 Adams Street, near Myrtle Ave.
- Myers Machine Works, 1903
  Machinery and engines. 116 27th Street
- N.Y. Patent Steam Carpet Beating and Restoration/Renovating Co., 1878, 1885, 1898
  Carpet cleaners. 74 Court, cor. Livingston
- N.Y. Staats-Zeitung, Brooklyn Office for Advertising, 1888
  Newspaper. 379 Fulton Street, opposite City Hall
- Nagel, August, 1884
  Tin smith. 480 Bergen St., 2 doors down from Flatbush
- Nager Electric Co., 1926, 1928, 1929
  Electrical engineers. 432 Broadway
- Namm, A.I. (& Son) / Namm Store, The, 1898, 1908, 1913, 1923, 1926, 1928, 1940
  Window dressings, department store. Fulton to Livingston St.--Hoyt St. to Elm Place
- Narrows Taxpayer Association, The, 1929
  11 78th Street
- Nash, Philip I., Dr., 1932
- Nassau, The, 1921
  Building & loan association. 2738 Atlantic Avenue
- Nassau Brewery [Grass & Co.]
  431 & 433 1st Street
- Nassau Dairy, The, 1890
  157 Court Street
- Nassau Fire Insurance Company of Brooklyn, The, 1862, 1863, 1876, 1878
  10 Court Street; 28 & 30 Court St., cor. Remsen
- Nassau Point Club Properties, Inc., 1919
  186 Remsen Street
- Nat-Al Service Station, Inc.
  Service station. Cor. Clinton & Flushing Avenues
- National Cash Register Company, The, 1901, 1916
  75 Court Street
- National Licorice Company, 1925
  Licorice candy maker. Bridge & John Streets
- National Parlor Suit Co., 1910
  Maker of parlor suits. 65 Raymond Street
- Nearing, W., 1870
  Coal and wood dealer. 111 Atlantic St., cor. Warren and Coumbia Sts.
- Neefus, D.J., 1880-1881
  Wheelwright and blacksmith. Washington Ave., near City Line
- Nelson & Co., 1882
  Shoe store. 118 Court Street
- Nesmith & Sons, 1881
  Storage. between Fulton and Catharine Ferries
- New Chicory Manufacturing Co., The, 1900
  Chicory processing. 417 North 1st St. [formerly 162-164 North 3rd St.]
- New Deal Garage
  Garage. 1171-1179 DeKalb Avenue
- New Lots, Town of, 1862, 1878, 1882
  D. Glander and Geo. W. Palmer, Collectors
- New Lots, Town of, Improvement Commission, 1873
- New Lots, Town of, School Tax, 1869, 1883
  William H. McKee, Collector
- New Mermaid Laundry, 1944
  2915 West 24th Street near Mermaid Avenue
- New York Biscuit Company, The, 1896
  Biscuit makers. Tenth Ave. Fifteenth & Sixteenth Sts.
- New York City Transit Authority, 1965
  370 Jay Street
- New York Condensed Milk Co., 1877
  60, 62, & 64 Park Place, cor. College Place
- New York Conservatory of Music, Brooklyn Branch, 1871, 1873
  128, 130 and 132 Court Street; 102, 103 & 106 Court Street
- New York Dyeing and Printing Establishment, 1875
  Dyeing and printing. 98 Duane Street
- New York Mets, 1995
  Shea Stadium, Flushing
- New York & New Jersey Telephone Co., The, 1894, 1896, 1898, 1907
  16 Smith Street; 81 Willoughby Street
- New York Tiling Co., 1906
  Tiling company. 70 Willoughby Street
- New York Vitrified Tile Co., The, 1899
  Tile makers. 79 Fourth Street
- Newman, Bennie, 1915
  Plate and windowglass dealer. 906 Myrtle Avenue, bet. Tompkins and Throop
- Newman, T.A. & L.H., 1860, 1923, 1937
  Dry goods dealer. 291 Fulton Street, bet. Johnson and Tillary; 305-307 Fulton St., 274-282 Washington St.
- News, The, 1924
  Newspaper. 25 Park Place, New York
- Newton, Albro J. Company, 1913
  Lumber dealer. Nevins & Union Sts.
- Newtown Creek Towing Company, 1898
  Tugboat towing. 129 Broad Street
- Niagara Fire Insurance Company of New York, 1895
  Insurance company. 189 & 191 Montague Street
- Niagara Steam Pump Works, 1876
  Steam pump manufacturers. 23, old 9, Adams Street
- Noble, Harry M., 1880
  Plumber and gas fitter. 1374 Fulton Street, bet. New York & Brooklyn Aves.
- Nochemson, L., 1891, 1896
  Glass dealer. 1844-1/2 Fulton St.; 1860 Fulton St., bet. Buffalo & Rochester Aves.
- Noden, Abraham, 1868
  Stationery dealer. 194 York Street
- Nodine, F.J., 1867
  Stables. 124-128 Pierrepont Street
- Noe, W.H., 1874, 1891
  Carpenter and builder. 256 & 258 State Street, bet. Boerum and Smith Sts.
- Noelsch, John, 1891
  Roofer. 154 McKibben St. [formerly 185 Boerum St.]
- Norris, F.D., 1873, 1883
  Carpenter and builder. 29 & 31 DeKalb Avenue
- Norris, Thomas, 1887-1888
  Metal worker. 975 Gates Ave., bet. Patchen & Ralph Aves.
- Norris, W., 1888-1889
  Roofer. 136 Park Avenue
- North American Actinolite & Asbestites Co., The, 1902
  Chemical manufacturer. 256 Maujer Street
- North American Iron Works, The, 1897
  Art metal work. 40 and 42 Walton St.
- North Brooklyn Iron Foundry, 1870
  Iron foundry. 28 Rodney St., near Kent Ave.
- North, N.L., Dr., 1894
  Doctor. 627 Bedford Avenue
- North Star Cleaners, 1953
  Furniture cleaners. 1485 St. Johns Place
- Northridge, W.J., 1868, 1877, 1878, 1880, 1887, 1888
  Painter. 18, 52, 56 Myrtle Avenue; 415 Gates Avenue
- Norton & Gorman, 1909
  Contractors. 303 Douglass Street, near Third Ave.
- Norton, Samuel J.L., 1872
  Feed, hay, and straw dealers. 130 Broadway (late South 7th St.)
- Norwegian America Line, 1934
  Shipping line
- Norwood, J., 1894
  Iron, wire, and brass works. 349 Adams Street, near City Hall
- Nottingham Association, 1930
  1363 E. 24th St.
- Nowlan, Peter, 1874
  Granite dealer. 24th St., near 5th Ave.
- Nungasser, William, 1898
  Coal dealer. 3rd Street, above 3rd Avenue
- Nuthmann, Theodore, 1871
  Ladies shoe maker. 158 Court Street
- Nutt, Furman T., 1873, 1881
  Hatmaker. 300 Fulton St.; 162 Pierrepont St.
- Nutting, A.J., 1888
  Tailor. 386 & 388 Fulton Street
- Nye & Titus, 1878
  Carpet dealer. 607, 609 & 611 Fulton St., opp. Flatbush Ave.
- O'Brien, Herbert A., 1898
  Livery stables. 17 & 19 Red Hook Lane
- O'Brien, John, 1893
  Painter. 270 Manhattan Avenue
- O'Brien, Joseph & Co., 1864, 1874, 1881
  Dry goods, clothing. 141-159 Atlantic Avenue
- O'Brien, M.C., 1930, 1932
  Realty & insurance. 798 Nostrand Avenue; 1184 Flatbush Avenue
- O'Bryan, M. Jr., 1880
  Plumber and gas fitter. 782 Fulton Street, corner of Adelphi
- O'Donohue Coffee Company, 1900
  Coffee roaster and dealer. Roasting plant, foot of Bridge St.
- O'Gara, John, 1898
  Horseshoer. Sixtieth Street, near Thirteenth Ave.
- O'Hanlon, P., 1874
  Millinery & accessories. 3 and 5 Greene Ave. and 491 Atlantic Ave.
- O'Hare, A.M., 1900, 1903
  Plumber. 1170 Third Avenue
- O'Keefe, John D., 1881
  Stables. 162 & 164 Carlton Avenue
- O'Keeffe & McKenna, 1892-1893
  Plumber. 467 Fifth Avenue
- O'Neill, P.F., 1859
  Dress trimmings dealer. 148 Atlantic Avenue
- O'Reilly, J. & J., 1870
  Dry goods dealer. 231 Fulton Street
- Oakes, Burdett S., 1860
  Undertaker. 726 Fulton St. [formerly 331 Washington St.]
- Oakes, Wm. W., 1885, 1887
  Metal worker. 377 Myrtle Avenue, cor. Clermont
- Oak-Leaf Press, 1938, 1941
  Printer. 1531, 1605, 1611 Flatbush Avenue
- Oakley & Sons, 1868, 1870, 1873
  Stables. 18 & 20 High Street, near Fulton; 21 and 23 Hoyt Street, near Fulton
- Oatman, Joseph A., 1881
  Painter & decorator. 135 Carlton Avenue, near Myrtle
- Obronko Studio, 1933
  Photographer. 132 Seventh Avenue
- Ochs, Phillip, 1888
  Baker. 107 Grand Street
- Offerman & Heissenbuttel, 1894
  Coal and wood dealer. foot of Jay Street
- Ogni Bros., 1890
  Religious statuary. 1665 Fulton St., opp. Schenectady Ave.
- Ohlman & Co., 1871
  Clothing maker. 115 Ewen Street, cor. Montrose Ave.